## **Mathew Tomberlin**

AR/VR Developer and Gameplay Engineer

Phone: (209) 338-7200

Email: mathew.tomberlin@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://mathewtomberlin.github.io

## **Summary**

#### AR/VR Software Engineer and Game Developer with 8+ years of experience

AR/VR developer with a specialty in advanced peripherals like tracking gloves, haptic gloves, and XR headsets. I built a haptic VR game that won AWE 2024's Best in Show, I've published a paper about new VR input methods, and I developed a therapeutic game for a PHD thesis. I also present VR demos for investors and conferences and design testing software for AR/VR hardware. Previously, I served as a Korean linguist and signals intelligence operator in the US Marine Corps.

#### **Skills**

- Game Engines: Unity and Unreal Engine
- Rendering: Shaders, Materials, Textures, Lighting
- Code: C#, C++, Blueprints, HLSL, OpenXR
- Gameplay: Physics, combat, AI, level design
- AR/VR Hardware (Oculus, Vive, Index)
- Hand/Body Tracking (Magnetic, bend, IR sensors)
- Optimization and Debugging
- 3D Modeling, Character Rigging & Animation

# Experience

## HaptX Inc. VR Software Engineer Mar 2022 - Oct 2024

- Shipped a VR game that won AWE 2024's Best of Show that showcased the new G1 haptic tracking gloves
- Shipped AR glove validation software still used by HaptX G1 glove assemblers at Advanced Input Systems (AIS)
- Optimized VR demo framerate by 100% via performance profiling and by debugging engine settings
- Enabled \$12 mil AIS investment and a Y-12 partnership by fixing broken tracking sensors for investor demos
- Gave 100+ VR demos to VIPs, including board members, HaptX investors, and ITSEC 2023 attendees
- Lectured to a CalPoly medical technology class on VR, AR, XR, haptics, and digital twins

#### Tapestry Solutions, a Boeing company

**Software Engineer** May 2019 -Mar 2022

- Developed Boeing ESI's internal simulation data processing using Apache Kafka
- Developed the ICODES Load Planner web app via requirements designed by government customers

#### **Undergraduate Researcher**

Game Developer Jan 2017 - Mar 2018

- Shipped Scalebridge, a VR game using an EEG headset, that was presented at VS-Games 2019 (PDF) Scalebridge: Adaptive Reasoning Proportional Reasoning Game
- **Developed Gauntlet, a VR input technique for hand tracking**, and published a paper about it at IEEE VR 2017 (PDF) Gauntlet: Travel Technique for Immersive Environments

#### **US Marine Corps**

**Korean Linguist and Sigint Operator** Oct 2007 - Jun 2012

Graduated from DLI, Monterey Bay with fluency in Korean and deployed operating intelligence equipment

#### **Projects**

#### **Block Breakout**

Open-source UE4 C++ Game

Oct 2018 -Nov 2018

- Unreal Engine 4 game developed with C++ as open-source project hosted on GitHub
- Source Code: <a href="https://github.com/MathewTomberlin/Breakout">https://github.com/MathewTomberlin/Breakout</a>

#### **Open Ocean VR**

Immersive Underwater VR Game Jan 2018 - Apr 2018

- Designed Unity tools for game designers, modeled and animated animals, and coded the creature behaviors
- Non-VR Version: https://gamejolt.com/games/OpenOcean/383524

#### **Just One Night**

2017 IEEE VR Gauntlet Technique VR Demo Jan 2017 - Mar 2017

- VR game with Leap Motion IR hand-tracking as demo of the Gauntlet VR technique, with art from Polish artists
- VR and Leap Motion Version: <a href="https://studentgames.itch.io/just-one-night">https://studentgames.itch.io/just-one-night</a>

### **Education**

CSU Monterey Bay Computer Science B.S. with Game Programming Concentration Aug 2016 -May 2018